export const quizQuestions_6 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'Which React concept is used for sharing stateful logic between components?',
      choices: ['State Reducers', 'Higher-Order Components', 'React Portals', 'Custom Hooks'],
      correctAnswer: 'Custom Hooks',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the main purpose of using keys in lists in React?',
      choices: ['To improve performance during updates', 'To uniquely identify each element', 'To enable accessibility features', 'Both A and B'],
      correctAnswer: 'Both A and B',
    },
    {
      question: 'How do you access a prop named “username” in a class component?',
      choices: ['this.props.username', 'props.username', 'this.username', 'React.props.username'],
      correctAnswer: 'this.props.username',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the default export from the "react" package?',
      choices: ['React', 'Component', 'ReactDOM', 'ReactElement'],
      correctAnswer: 'React',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can you improve the performance of a React application?',
      choices: ['Minimizing state usage', 'Using React.memo for components', 'Reducing the number of DOM elements', 'All of the above'],
      correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
    },
    {
      question: 'What does the term “declarative” mean in the context of React?',
      choices: ['Declaring variables explicitly', 'React automatically manages the DOM updates', 'Specifying the logic of the rendering process', 'Using declarative programming paradigms only'],
      correctAnswer: 'React automatically manages the DOM updates',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the role of the "ReactDOM" package in a React application?',
      choices: ['For managing the state', 'For rendering components to the DOM', 'For handling routing', 'For creating functional components'],
      correctAnswer: 'For rendering components to the DOM',
    },
    {
      question: 'Which of the following is NOT a valid React hook?',
      choices: ['useState', 'useEffect', 'useComponent', 'useContext'],
      correctAnswer: 'useComponent',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the "useReducer" hook in React?',
      choices: ['For state management using a reducer function', 'For reducing the memory usage', 'For decreasing the number of renders', 'For combining multiple reducers'],
      correctAnswer: 'For state management using a reducer function',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is a typical use case for the "useContext" hook in React?',
      choices: ['For local state management', 'For sharing data across many components', 'For handling user input', 'For managing side effects'],
      correctAnswer: 'For sharing data across many components',
    }
  ]
};
